and the Mordovian language is not artificial. So
а Мордовский язык искусственный нет Так
wait. So you can say there
подождите Так можно сказать там и
Khazar and Turkic and Mongolian and
Хазарский и тюркский и монгольский и
Russian Well, maybe some words
русский Ну может быть какие-то слова
were borrowed Yes, like in all
были заимствованы Да как как и во всех
languages, but mostly in the main part Yes,
языках но в основном в основной часть Да
it still remained primitive Well, I didn’t
он всё равно остался первобытный Ну не
say  would be a primitive but Ukrainian language
сказал бы первобытный но украинский язык
Yes, it came
Да он произошёл
from a large group of Slavic languages, but
от большой группы славянских языков но
Russian was considered the language of the Slavs Hello Hello, I’m from
русский Здравствуйте Здравствуйте я из
the city of Khmelnitsky Are you
города Хмельницкий Вы
from the Republic of Mordovia Saransk No
откуда республика Мордовия Саранск Нет
where from 80 km from Saransk village you Erz
откуда 80 км от Саранска деревня вы эрз
Moksha
мокша
Erz my father is Moksha And what
эрз у меня отец мокша А с какой он
region is he from Oh  from the region Well, he’s from Saransk
области Ой из района Ну он из Саранска
himself, he’s
сам
never been to Saransk. The fact is
Саранске не был никогда моши был Дело в
that I have a grandfather, yes Grandfather. He was from
том что у меня дед да Дед Он был с
some village and his father was already in the
какой-то деревни а отец он уже При
Soviet Union. He studied in Saransk and
Советском Союзе Он учился в Саранске и
Well, like, he was born in Saransk because his
Ну типа он родился в Саранске потому что
grandfather  My grandmother has already moved to Saransk, I don’t
дед переехал уже в Саранск бабушка не
know who she is Erz or Moksha or Russian, and my
знаю кто она эрз или мокша или русская а
mother turns out to be Ukrainian. Mom worked in
мама у меня украинка получается Мама в
Mordovia.
Мордовии
In the Soviet Union, she worked as a doctor, as in
работала При Советском Союзе лекарем как
Russian, a doctor. So they
это по-русски доктором Вот и они там
got married there. And then they moved
женились А потом переехали в воде
here in the seventh year, as the main one.
седьмом году сюда назна како главную
no street, I’m
улицу нет я
still I, look, I was little, I was
всё я ж я смотрите я был маленький я был
little, I was a couple of years old then, that
маленький мне пару лет было тогда так то
is, I don’t remember anything at all, and we
есть я вообще ничего не помню и мы
got relatives, some distant
получа родственники какие-то дальние
relatives there, but we
родственники там есть но мы с ними
never supported them, as if during the
никогда не поддерживали как бы При
Soviet Union  There wasn’t even the Internet
Советском Союзе не было и интернета
to support me like that, yes.
чтобы так поддерживать да
Well, my father called by telegraph. He
Ну у меня отец звонил по телеграфу Он
went to the Count.
ходил на Граф
Somehow they managed to get through and
там как-то получатся дозванивались а
then my grandfather was gone. But these
потом деда там не стало А вот эти
cousins ​​And so on. In short, things
двоюродные И так дальше Короче с ними
didn’t work out with them. In general, I  I don’t
как-то там не сложилось В общем я их не
know what you’re talking about, yes, you know with
знаю о чём общаетесь ту да вы знаете с
Ukraine, probably only the war is
Украиной наверно только войне
more good, here’s how this
больше хорошо вот вам как эте
ru against Ukraine is very hard, in fact
ру против Украины очень тяжело на самом
it’s hard. I just have a wife from Ukraine,
тяжело У меня просто жена ещё с Украины
so it’s very damn see how how how how
поэтому очень блин видите как как как
interesting the Soviet Union coincided  my father
интересно Советский Союз Да у моего отца
had a wife from Ukraine. I once went to
была жена из Украины Я ездил когда-то в
Moscow to work. Well, in my
Москву на заработки Ну в своей молодости
stormy youth, I visited Moscow many times
бурной молодости Я много раз в Москве
and met a girl
бывал и познакомился на рынке с девочкой
from
с
Ukraine at the market, and I’m speaking from the republic, she did
украино а я говорю с республики там она
n’t even know where it
даже и не знала где это
was.  I
находится
took it to myself, then I took it to myself for the second time, we
нук себе взял потом второй раз к себе
got married. We also succeed.
взял поженились У нас тоже получается Я
When I say, well, I tell you that my father is
когда вот ну Рассказываю что у меня отец
from Mordovia. Yes, everyone is such a country,
сам из Мордовии Да все такие страна
no, it’s now like Mordor, like, yes,
нене это сейчас уже типа Мордор типа да
as
как
they say. And before, it was like, well, Mordovia is
говорят А раньше как бы ну Мордовия
somewhere in general, Like, he thinks that  this is
гдето вообще Типа думает что это
some kind of
какая-то
country, honestly an awesome republic I'll
страна честно республика офигенная Я
show you now I also have my
сейчас покажу у меня ещё у меня ещё есть
father's
отцовская
uh embroidered shirt Mordovian
ээ вышиванка Мордовская
now with our eight-pointed Yes
сейчас вот с нашей восьмиконечной й Да
this is Mordovian yes
это это Мордовская да
yes Mordovian the Udmurts also have
да Мордовская у удмуртов тоже есть
Mordovians yes So I'm saying this is
мордов да Так я же говорю это от отца
left from my father  more Oh, how he loved her very much,
мне осталось ещё О как бы он очень любил
here he is Well, it wasn’t customary here Yes,
её вот он Ну тут не было принято Да
wearing embroidered shirts During the Soviet Union,
ходить в вышиванках При Советском Союзе
but he has this shirt By the way,
во но у него вот эта руба Кстати как
because well, I call it an embroidered shirt But an
потому что ну я её называю вышиванка Но
embroidered shirt is in Ukrainian and this is not an
вышиванка - это по-украински а это не
embroidered shirt  shirt Well, it
вышиванка она рубаха Ну рубаха она
was a shirt, well, it’s just that the advice started all over
рубаха была ну просто советы всё пере
again Yes, and I see that they
пере начали Да и Причём я смотрю вот у
don’t have Mordovian Names, but I
не есть мордовские Название но я вам не
can’t tell you So, me too, yes, I wanted to
могу сказать Вот я тоже да я я хотел
know Because I’m interested in what to
узнать Потому что мне интересно как
call all these traditions of my ancestors
называть всё такие традиции моих предков
Business  the thing is that it’s interesting that I, uh, my
Дело в том что вот интересно я э у меня
mother is Ukrainian, yes, the Ukrainians also have
мать украинка да у них у украинцев тоже
embroidered shirts, they have their own ornaments there;
типа вышиванки есть там свои орнаменты
the father, yes, everyone has a region there, and the
отец Да у каждый тем боле обла там да
father is like Moksha, too. And I looked, I
отец мокша типа тоже И я смотрел я
looked at the websites of
смотрел на сайтах у
uh in Mordovia, a huge number of different ones  there
ээ в Мордовии огромное количество разных
are embroidered patterns, yes, but the Russians, No, I
вышитых узоров есть да а у русских Нет я
ask the Russians, a Where is your tradition,
у русских спрашиваю а Где ваша традиция
yes For example, I say that I am
да Вот например я говорю что я
half Mordvin, half Ukrainian,
наполовину мордвин наполовину украинец
and both the Ukrainians and the
да и у украинцев и
Mordovians have their own traditions, their
у мордвы есть свои традиции свои
embroidered shirts, and their embroidered shirts, and where are the
вышиванки Да свои вышитые рубахи А где
wedding ceremonies?  I
свадебные обряды Да вот а я русским
say to the Russians, you can say your own at least one
говорю можете свою хоть одну свадебную
folk wedding song, no, they don’t have it. It’s
песню народную сказать нету у них нету
just there. It’s just that many have forgotten
Просто есть Просто многие позабыли
because this Soviet Union is it.
потому что этот Советский Союз он Вот
Chop everything at the root like this. Yes, even
Всё на корню вот так порубай так Да даже
before the Soviet Union. Like if you look at
до Советского Союза Типа если смотришь
the publication there. Didn’t they have these rituals? Yes
издание там Нели они были эти обряды Да
they were there in the Ivanovo region, I know
они были там в Ивановской области я знаю
because I have friends from Ivanovo region, they
потому что у меня друзья с Ивановской
invited me to a wedding in the Ivanovo
меня на свадьбу приглашали в Ивановской
region. I was at a wedding in the Ivanovo
области Я был на свадьбе в Ивановской
region, it’s in the north north of Moscow,
области это на севере северней Москвы
so Ivano, look, the Ivanovo region is
так Ивано смотрите Ивановская область -
also not Russian. The Ivanovo region
это ж тоже не русский Ивановская область
is also native.  Finno-Ugric peoples
это исконно тоже фино угорские народы
Here we are Marva, I wouldn’t say that there is no
Вот мы марва я бы так не сказал там не
there no Finno-Ugric well, just like they were
там нету фино угорский ну как и их
recorded as Russians, look. The fact is that
записали в русских смотри Дело в том что
as it is now, just like here in
как сейчас так же как у нас вот в
Mordovia Yes, if I look now at
Мордовии Да если я смотрю сейчас
the census Yes, almost all Russians are there  they
перепись Да там почти всех русских
are recording Yes, and the youth of Erz Mo they are also
записывают Да и молодёжь эрз мо они тоже
recording here and What year are you Well, the
записывают вот а Какого года ты Ну вот
last one that was shown recently and
последнюю которую недавно показывали да
then what the last one was 2 years ago
то там какая последняя была 2 года назад
They were held last year or
Они проводились в прошлом году или в
this year they didn’t
этом году они е
publish no the placenta was in 2002
опубликовали нет послед была в 2002 году
No now  I'll show you the last
Нет вот сейчас я вам покажу последняя
census a couple of years ago was
перепись пару лет назад была
now not it was a couple of years ago but it
сейчас не она была пару пару лет но она
was electronic and I'm still here for the twenty-
была электронной и я ещ вот двадцать
first year, here's the twenty-first year, the
первый год вот двадцать первый год
Russian census Yes, and the results
Российская перепись Да и результаты
were presented because I looked,
представили потому что я смотрел
analyzed and many, I met a
анализировал и многие вот я встречал
guy too,
парень тоже
uh  he says I’m from the True Census,
ээ он говорит я из Правдивая перепись
it was 2002 when I was still around, I
это была 2002 года когда я был ещё мне
was then about
было тогда сколько
12 something like that and a postman really came to us
12 что-то такое и к нам пришла
with this
действительно почтальон с этой вот этой
waste paper and sat down in our
макулатуры села к нам во
yard dad passport mother grandmother everyone was here and the
двор батя паспорт мать бабушка тут все и
children came running and  she wrote down everyone there
прибежали дети и она всех записала там
who is Marvin Who is Russian It was
кто Марвин Кто русский вот Это была
really because she walked from
действительно потому что она ходила из
the courtyard of the
двора
Military District and all the
вво и всех
heads in the electronic area there you can
зава в электронной площади там можешь
write Azerbaijani Marvin there is Kyrgyz
написать азербайджанец Марвин там киргиз
or Yakut or I don’t know
или якут или не знаю
Dagestani this is not a census so that’s the essence of the
дагестанец это не перепись так вот суть
World Cup The point is that
ЧМ Суть в том что
many  they signed up for the Russians because,
многие они записывались в русские потому
well,
что как бы вот
I wouldn’t say that, I honestly wouldn’t say that,
ну не сказал я бы честно так не сказал
my everyone
мои все
knows me, I
знакомы с м я
communicate with them, I wrote here, Believe me, honestly,
общаюсь писал вот Поверь мне ну честно
because I cook in this team all the
нас потому что я в этом коллективе всё
time, Well, maybe there 10 Protsev
время варю Ну может быть там Процев 10
would still be Russians  They called themselves Yes, I may have been
бы ещё русскими себя назвали Да я может
mistaken, but 80% would have been called the same
быть и ошибся но 80% бы назвали так же
as the Ivanovo region Yes, if we
как Ивановская область Да если мы
look at
смотрим
the maps of the settlement of the Slavs Previously Yes, there
ээ карты расселения славян Раньше Да там
were no Merya tribes living there Meshchera And
не было там жили племена меря Мещера И
so on Yes They just later took them
так дальше Да Во их просто потом взяли
all and called them all Russian Yes at first  I grew up very
всех назвали русскими Да сначала велико
well, I know the beginning of these tribes, but I was in the
рос знаю нач этих племён но я был в
Ivanovo region at a weak point, I’m
Ивановской области на слабе я тебе
telling you. That is, they have
говорю То есть то есть у них по-другому
everything differently with us, they have it
всё у нас вот по-другому у них
differently, then I was still in the south there, well, the
по-другому потом я был ещё на юге там ну
south of Russia is Krasnodar  region, too, at a
юг России это Краснодарский край тоже на
wedding they have a completely different way there, that
свадьбе у них вообще по-другому там
is, there, also take Many of the so-
всё то есть там э также возьми Многие
called Russian folk songs
так называемые русские народные песни
that they give out are Mordovian yes
которые они выдают это мордовские да
Songs that
Песни которые
rum And you know there are such e Chuvash Yes, I
рум А ты знаешь есть такие е Чуваши Да
know the Chuvash, but they are Chuvash It turns out they are,
Чуваши знаю но Чуваши они Получается они
as it were  The heirs of Vosko and the Bulgarians, they are
как бы Наследники Воско и булгарии они
partly Turkic, partly
частично тюрки частично вот непонятно
their origin is unclear, Nenya Well, it’s clear
ихнее происхождение неня Ну понятно Ну
Well, look, here we have Mordovia Yes, my
вот смотри вот у нас Мордовия Да мой
district is
район
Atyashevsky, this is our extreme Eastern district
атяшевский это крайний Восточный район у
My district is divided by the river
нас Мой район разделяет река
Alar Alatyr Yes Alatyr Yes Alatyr are
Аларь Алатырь Да Алатырь Да Алатырь вот
on one side standing on the same bank
на одной стороне стоят на одном берегу
there are Mordovian villages on the other
стоят мордовские деревни на другом
bank of the Chuvash Well, in the Chuvash,
берегу чувашский Ну чу в чуваший же вот
this is an Alatar region that wanted to separate from the
это алатар район хотел отделиться от
Chuvash so that it would be taken like in, in
чуваший чтобы его забрали типа в
my opinion, to this well, it may have
по-моему в эту ну это может быть
happened once, but it will never
когда-то это и было но это никогда и не
happen because there are people there  they live and
будет потому что там люди живут и
talk We speak a different
разговаривают Сосем на другом
language,
языке
and the people there are a little
у и люди там немножко
slanted Well, they have a little epicanthus,
раскосы Ну у них немножко есть эпикантус
this is a Jurassic feature, yes, you understand. There is a
это юрская особенность да понимаешь Вот
river flowing on one side of the Mordva on the
речка течёт на одной стороне Мордва на
other,
другой
the Chuvash are common, even common words, maybe
Чуваши общий даже общие слова может быть
we have them there, I compared Yes, there is some
есть у нас там я вот сравнивал Да есть
fork, plate and glass, there may
кака вилка тарелка и бокал там может
be something similar there, but the main ones are all
быть что-то похожее есть но основные все
these grandfather, head,
эти дедушка башка
words, some ancient ancient Yes, they are
слова кое е древние древние Да они
generally radically different Well,
вообще кардинально отличаются Ну потому
because these words are new Yes,
что вот эти слова которые новые Да
objects also appeared some time there
появились предметы также кою время там
Tsarist time they may have appeared A  these are the
Царское время они может появились А вот
old words that there is a bed there is a table
те слова старые которые там кровать стол
there is some kind of utensils, elements of everyday life Yes,
там какая-то утварь элементы бы быта Да
it is completely different and the people and the
она вообще полностью отличается и люди и
people’s mentality are even a little different. I
люди менталитетом даже немножко другие
can honestly say that we will allow them to be like
Вот честно могу сказать мы допустим там
that there, they are a little like that, but still it’s
такие они немножко такие но всё равно мы
like we go to visit a friend
как бы ходим в гости друг
friend, how are you now with learning your
другу как как у вас сейчас с изучением
native language, everything is already fine at school
родного языка уже всё отлично в школе
please, just like two lessons a
пожалуйста только как бы как два урока в
week Yes, four lessons that’s right,
неделю Да четыре урока вот Ну правильно
but keep in mind that it’s being studied as a foreign language.
но имей в виду что он как иностранный
Why not if it’s on par
изучается Да почему на не если наравне
with you?  mathematics in Chuva oh
это значи у вас бы математика на чува ой
this
на этом
would be studied physics in
изучалась бы физика на
Mordovian no physics not in Mordovian
мордовском нет физика не на мордовском
physics in Russian in general and grammar
физика на русском на общ а грамматика
there spelling is the language Mordovian plus
там орфография есть язык Мордовский плюс
Mordovian region another additional lesson
Мордовский край ещё дополнительный урок
studying the Republic justification Who
изучение Республики обоснование Кто
came who left when it is that glaciers are not
пришёл кто ушёл когда это что ледники не
glaciers What periods Here  this is all there
ледники Какие периоды Вот это всё есть
right up to the Soviet period there, when
вплоть до советского там периода когда
Mordovia participated in the Great
Мордовия участвовала в Великой
Patriotic War, how it helped,
Отечественной войне как она помогала
plus before Brezhnev, before Brezhnev’s times,
плюс до брежневки до брежневских времён
in short, I just realized that it turns out that
короче вот понял просто получается что
yes, look, this is the same as it was during the
да вот смотрите это так же как было При
Soviet Union in Ukraine, and what
Советском Союзе в Украине да что
did they do with the Ukrainian language? Just like that
украинский язык делали Просто вот так
since you now study Mordovian a couple of times a
как у вас сейчас Мордовский пару раз в
week and it’s all an artificial
неделю изучаешь и всё это искусственный
language that brother Let’s not talk about Ukraine,
язык что брат Давай не будем про Укра
Ukrainian is artificial Well, it consists
украинский искусственный Ну он состоит
of four or five languages
из э четырёх или пяти языков
Well, well, explain to me the Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth Yes, the
Ну а Ну обоснуй мне ну речи посполитая
great Kingdom of Lithuania, the
Да великое Литовское
Russian Empire and a little  a
царство Российская империя и немножко
little bit of the Khazar Kaganate for
чуть-чуть хазарского каганата
you Well, you
вам Ну это
know, when there is a border of the empire
знаешь вот когда есть граница империи
when you mix this many things are
когда намеши вот это множество всего
good, but the Mordovian language is artificial,
хорошо а Мордовский язык искусственный
no. So wait. So you can say there
нет Так подождите Так можно сказать там
Khazar and Turkic and Mongolian and
и Хазарский и тюркский и монгольский и
Russian Well, maybe some words
русский Ну может быть какие-то слова
were borrowed yes  As in all
были заимствованы да Как и во всех
languages, but mostly in the main part. Yes,
языках но в основном в основной части Да
it still remains primitive. Well, he
он ВС равно остался первобытный Ну
said, the primitive language is Ukrainian. Yes,
сказал первобытный но украинский язык Да
it came
он произошёл
from a large group of Slavic languages, but the
от большой группы славянских языков но
Russian language was considered the
единым языком славян считался русский
single language of the Slavs.
язык единым языком славян считался
I’ll understand Serb and I’ll
есть я Серба пойму как раз да поляка
understand Pole, but I don’t understand Russian, that is, I
пойму а русский не пойму то есть я
understand correctly, I don’t understand, that is, it’s not
правильно понимаю я не пойму то есть не
Serb, not Pole.
Серба не поляка Окей правильно понимаю
year is normal So they
до двадцать второго года нормально Так
traded there and communicated Yes, wait,
это торговали там общались Да подожди
all the Slavic languages ​​came from Russian I
все славянские языки пошли от Русского Я
heard you correctly Yes, I don’t know who came
правильно тебя услышал Да не знаю кто
from where it came to me, this is generally
откуда пошёл мне вот это вообще
purple Who goes where Can you tell who
фиолетово Кто куда А можешь сказать кто
when if the Ukrainian language is artificial
когда если украинский язык искусственный
who when for a population of fifty million
кто когда для пятидесяти миллионного
invented this language  wait, the
населения придумал этот язык погоди
Belarusian language is artificial no
белорусский язык искусственный нет
artificial oh this is real,
искусствен ой этот настоящий
that is, Ukrainian is real Belarusian is
то есть украинский настоящий белорусский
real Yes, and Serbian is also real I
настоящий Да а сербский тоже настоящий
know all the real languages ​​in m you speak
зна все настоящие языки в м ты говоришь
Ukrainian artificial I’m just saying
украинский искусственный просто говорю
that in Ukraine there is a mixture of languages ​​because
что в Украине языков намешано потому что
Ivanofrankivsk speaks its own
иванофранковск разговаривает на своём
language, that’s the same as in that  I speak the same language
языке это так на каком на таком же языке
as I do in Khmelnitsky My
как я в Хмельницком разговариваю Моя
wife from Western Ukraine
жена Западной украи
understands the pain with
понима те боль с
some words. Take Britain.
некоторые слова Вот ты возьми Британию
Yes, in England, too, some people
Да в Англии тоже одни граст и другие
speak a little differently, she doesn’t
могут немножко по-разному говори она не
understand the people I speak
понимает тех людей которые разговариваю
in Germany, look in Germany, the German
в Германии смотри в Германии немецкий
language is there  and Polish German Yes, in
язык там и польский немецкий Да в
Germany for example You listen to a person from
Германии например Ты послушай человек из
Bavaria Yes and a person
Баварии Да и человек
from
из
this Lorraine or something or whatever you
этой лотарингии какой-то там или что там
don’t understand just like Mordovians
не понимать также как и вот Мордва
Chuvash Yes it seems that
Чуваши Да вроде
the languages ​​there are even a little similar but
вот языки там даже немножко похожи но
good And when when Ukrainian if
хорошо А когда вот когда украинский если
it  artificial language Yes, when was it
это язык искусственный Да когда его
invented and who came up with it? In short, I
придумали и кто придумал зась Короче я
expressed myself incorrectly, I understood everything when
неправильно выразился всё понял когда
someone
кто кого мне
understood whom, I’m just interested, so
вообще понял просто мне интересно так
look at the question, it turns out that you, uh, the
смотри вопрос получается что у вас э
Mordovian language, uh, are taught simply so that there
Мордовский язык ээ учат просто так что
is a Mordovian language, but
вот есть Мордовский язык но всё
we do everything else in  Russian Yes, well, the
остальное мы делаем на русском Да ну
main subjects are studied in
основные предметы изучаются на русском
Russian; mathematics, physics,
языке математика физика
geometry, this is in Russian because there are the
геометрия это на русском потому что там
basic laws that Ani’s scientists deduced
основные законы которые выводили учёные
in Russian, not in Mordovian,
Ани на русском языке не на мордовском
stop, scientists, for example, let’s take Maxwell there,
стоп учёные например возьмём там максвел
yes, when he studied field theory, yes, he studied
да когда теорию поля вот да изучал он
electromagnetic all sorts of things there. Yes, he
там электромагнитные всякие штуки Да он
Zaton wrote in Russian in Russian
на русском языке писал Затон на русском
No, he wrote in English
писал Нет он писал на английском
for general use for all regions of
для общего пользования для всех регионов
Russia that do not speak
России которые не разговаривают на
Russian so that everyone has the same
русском чтобы у всех было одинаковые
conditions and everyone is transferred to the Russian
условия и всех пересадили на русский
language yes this is assimilation yes this is normal
язык да это ассимиляция да это нормально
Well, look Why also Under
Вот ну смотрите Почему также При
Soviet  Union of Azerbaijanis Yes, they
Советском Союзе азербайджанцам Да
were forced to learn physics since they have a
заставляли учить физику пор у них есть в
school in Azerbaijan, and again some
Азербайджане школа да ещё раз некоторые
there are, but the Azerbaijanis teach in
есть но азербайджанцы учат по
Azerbaijani Yes, the Kazakhs teach
азербайджанский Да казахи учат на
physics, mathematics in Kazakh, what is the
казахском языке физику математику в чём
problem with
проблема
schools in Azerbaijan, they study the Russian language
школ в Азербайджане изучают русский язык
super, we also had
супер учат у нас в Украине тоже были
Russian-language schools in Ukraine  everything is super in
русскоязычные школы всё супер в
Kazakhstan there are Russian speakers, but the Kazakhs
Казахстане есть русскоязычные но казахи
now teach in Kazakh why. For example,
теперь учат на казахском почему Например
Turks can learn
турки на турецком языке могут учить да
physics and mathematics in Turkish, but Kazakhs and
физику и математику а казахи и
Azerbaijanis are also Turks, someone
азербайджанцы тоже тюрки не могут кто-то
can speak English, someone can speak
может английский чать кто-то Может там
Italian, German there, Spanish and
итальянский немецкий там испанский а
someone else...  then the Russian is in the World Cup problem I don’t see
кто-то русский в ЧМ пробле Я не вижу у
you have any problems with the language I’m
тебя какие-то проблемы с языком Я вас
asking you That’s why it turns out that the
спрашиваю Вот почему так получается что
people who received their
намер народы которые получили свою
independence are the Kazakhs Azerbaijanis Yes,
независимость казахи азербайджанцы Да
they teach in their own languages ​​And
они на своих языках да типа учат А
others are like the same Tatars Chuvash Yes
другие вот на те же татары Чуваши Да
Mordovians  The Chuvash Mard people, our people, always and
Мордва Чуваши мард люди наши всегда и
always spoke Russian, even
всегда все разговаривали на русском даже
in a remote village in a remote village
в деревне в глухой в деревне
when no one understood each other
когда Просто никто друг друга не понимал
and they switched between the pestilence and you
и переходили меду мор вами переходили
always switched to Russian Because they understood each other, you
всегда на русский Потому что друг друга
understand in a remote village we
понимали понимаешь в глухой деревне мы
also rode on the Strelka with  in the
также и с
Chuvash there are Tatar villages, you
чувашах есть татарские деревни ты об
don’t know about it. I
этом не знаешь
understand. I mean, I don’t
Понятно В смысле не
know. You know that in the Chuvash there are
знаю Ты знаешь что в Чуваши есть
Tatar villages and Mari villages, there are other
татарские деревни и марийские деревни
villages in the Chuvash, there are some other ones, so
деревни есть ещё какие ещё какие так
Tatars. Well, like there are Mordovian ones, well, I’ll
татарс Ну типа мордовские есть это ну я
say more Bash is great  not me from
больше скажу Баш великолепно не я из
Look I'm studying The fact is that I'm an
Смотри Я изучаю Дело в том что я я
ethnographer not me I didn't say that I'm saying
этнограф не я Я не сказал что я говорю
that in Bashkortostan there are also Tatar
что в Башкортостане также есть татарские
villages there are Mari villages there are
деревни есть марийские деревни есть
Bashkor yes that is, on the border of the Republic there is
башкор да то есть на погранич Республики
a lot of confusion when if there are any problems
очень меся когда если какие-то проблемы
we all go over
мы все переходим на русский язык
you understand the Russian language, it’s universal, so
понимаешь он универсальный поэтому для
it’s convenient for this in Russia Uh-huh, I understand.
этого в России это удобно Угу понял А
But the question you have is that they study your
вот вопрос У вас изучают э ваши там
national culture there, poets,
национальную культуру там поэтов
writers, Mordovian poets, writers. We all
писателей мордовски поэты писатели Всё у
have what kind of
нас есть какие какие вы знаете
Mordovian writers do you know, now I can’t
мордовских писателей сейчас я не могу
remember because it  the school
вспомнить потому что это школьная
curriculum, well, the Russians are good, and you
программа вот а а русских хорошо а
can name some Russian writers.
русских писателей можете назвать
Well, Pushkin is there,
Ну Пушкин там
Tolstoy is there, you see, this is also the school
Толстой есть видите это тоже школьная
curriculum, but you named the Russians, and the great ones in the
программа но русских вы назвали а мордов
Russian Empire were those
великих в Российской империи были те
great ones who were you, the kings
великие которые которы было вы царям
benefited from the Ukrainian great writers
выгодно были украинские великие писатели
on  that moment when there was
на тот момент когда был
Pushkin Levsky wrote yet I don’t know him
Пушкин левский написал ещ я его не знаю
let’s say You know, well, because yes, the
допустим Знаете ну так Потому что да
Soviet Union didn’t want you to
Советский Союз не хотел чтобы вы его
know him Yes, I know, they taught you at school You see,
знаешь Да знаю учили в школе Вот видишь
And I don’t know Kotlyarevsky because you
А я Котляревского не знаю потому что
see because look from the Soviet
видишь потому что смотри со Советский
Union yes uh  I tried to turn all of you
Союз да э пробовал из вас всех сделать
into Russians, but you don’t even
русских манкуртом да ты же даже не
know, I’m half Ukrainian Yes, and
знаешь вот Я украинец наполовину Да а
half Marvin I know my Ukrainian
наполовину Марвин Я знаю украинских
poets, I know my
своих вот этих поэтов знаю своих
Ukrainian writers Yes, Chu Ivitsky and so on
украинских писателей Да чу ивицкий и так
Further Yes But you studied with you and you
Дальше Да А вот у вас ты учился и ты с
know the modo  you in Mordovizhi besides
модо знаешь ты в мордови жи кроме
the kovskiy there was anyone other than Ko Panas rny
ковского ещ был кто кроме ко Панас рный
Tamtsky Lesya Ukrainka Ivan Franko so
там цкий Леся Украинка Иван Франко так
heaps Franko Lesya monthly five
кучах Франко Леся меся рный пять
pieces you told me three I told you five
штук ты ты мне назвал три я тебе пять
call the Russians let's let's
называй русских давай давай давай будем
take turns You call the Russian I'm the
по очереди Ты называешь русского я
Ukrainian come on No  I'm Russian Come
украинского давай Не я русских Давай
on, come on because you You counted five
давай потому что ты Ты посчитал пять
Let's see who's Ukrainian or
штук Давай посмотрим кто украинских или
you're Russian let's not have five Come on Name
ты русских давай не пять Давай Назови ты
three you named Russians Name
три назвал русских Назови ещё
two more who I named You named Pushkin
два кого я назвал Ты назвал Пушкин
Tolstoy someone else well Lerman let's
Толстой ещё кто-то ну Лерман давай ещё
name two more there's a lot of them  was Come on, I
называй там их много было Давай я всех
won’t remember everyone, I’m not a writer But I will remember
не вспомню я я не литерат А я вспомню
Come on That is, you were able to name three
Давай То есть ты три смог назвать
Who has more I can continue to name
У кого больше я могу и дальше назвать
Come on, you name five I named the sixth, you’re the sixth,
Давай ты навь пять я назва шестого ты
I’m the seventh,
шестого я седьмого
let’s be honest, I didn’t go deep into
давай честно я не углублялся в
literature I don’t like her  come on
литературу Она мне не нравится давай
Marco ovochok
Марко вовчок
Let's go on, let's look, I've already named this
Дай дальше давай смотри я уже сем назвал
And you've already named three
А ты три
Strikes Strike, even with the sounds it's
Страйка Страйка у тебя даже со звуками
bad let's Name even the fifth Come on even the
плохо давай Назови чет
fifth, name them
пятого Давай чет пятого называй
invented there come on
придумали там давай давай
come on whoever those Taras
давай кого те Тарас
Shevchenko shevchenko here I'm the only one
Шевченко шевченку вот я единствен
Shevchenko I've already told you nine you've already told me  three
Шевченко Я тебе уже девять назвал ты три
you can’t give birth you can’t give birth to Russian
ты не можешь родить ты не можешь русских
writers poets
писателей поэтов
complete victory
родить полная перемога
ass subscribe to th Telegram right now
попка подпишись на й Telegram прям зараз
he’s a
он а
pok ce even more and more respectfully YouTube taking
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through skarg or to your ban and even
нас через скарг ор в твый бан и дуже
more videos I don’t show people at the moment I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about  Stream Tomu for this
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
purpose, we need to write a Mali operational link
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
right away and while there in telegra
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okm video sche tezh Tsikava and Korisna
окм видео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we will blame you on trima
информация и мы повинни вами трима
postiyny
постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
in the same time, show you about it
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write Y
пиши Y